# Jarod Daming

jmdaming@gmail.com 812-660-2475 8420 Southport Dr. Evansville, IN 47711

## **Professional Summary**

Software Engineer with five years of experience gathering requirements, completing thorough analysis, and delivering practical and effective solutions to business needs. Worked to maintain, improve, and modernize legacy application systems in the financial industry. Able to complete projects efficiently and effectively with minimal supervision and direction.

# Areas of Expertise

- Programming and Design
- Gathering Requirements
- Project Management
- Data Structuring

- Excellent Problem-Solving Skills
- Strong Collaborative Skills
- Ability to Adapt
- Strong Interpersonal Skills

# Work Experience

Onemain Financial - Evansville, IN

Software Engineer

July 2017 - Present

- Assisted in design effort to bring ACAPS and BureauLink to 24x7 systems; expected to increase system uptime enabling enhanced customer connectivity and add additional revenue
- Designed and implemented front-end changes to streamline problem analysis; vastly decreased our turn-around time when working problem tickets
- Created new SQL processes to help identify issues before they begin and mitigate impact; able to identify incoming application dumps from third parties and resolve the issue before it brings down our system
- Successfully developed mentorship program at the request of the department's Vice President to help develop future leaders of the organization
- Maintained system level documentation and ensured process modifications were documented thoroughly
- Provide 24x7 support for ACAPS and BureauLink and respond effectively to issues

#### Programmer Analyst Sr

March 2015 – July 2017

- Designed installation plan and successfully implemented eSolutions front-end interface for XYCOR insurance system; this gave our business unit the option between green screens and a web-based front-end
- Assisted in Onemain Financial conversion; this conversion merged our two systems and led to Onemain Financial becoming the leader in personal lending
- Assisted in Lendmark data conversion and implemented system processes to keep data legally separate; complied with Department of Justice ruling on Springleaf-Onemain merger
- Served as 24x7 support for XYCOR systems

#### **Programmer Analyst**

December 2013 - March 2015

- Designed and implemented in-claim process; prevented call centers from contacting customers that had multiple policies when they already had a claim outstanding. Resulted in decreased service call counts
- Implemented Datarray data modeling system migration from DB2 to SQL Server; this would serve as the foundation from the eSolutions implementation
- Served as a primary point of contact in implementation of IBM Rational Developer for System Z (RDz) and training; this tool has since become department standard

#### Intern

May 2013 - December 2013

- Effectively implemented incoming projects and documented changes
- Completed COBOL and legacy system training

#### Indiana Tube Corporation – Evansville, IN

Intern

May 2012 - May 2013

- Managed reporting software in the sales, quality, and payroll departments; ensured accurate results and distribution were completed successfully
- Responsible for data management and design; worked with Sybase DBMS to confirm data quality
- Documented manufacturing processes and created training material; currently used during employee training period

## Education

## University of Southern Indiana – Evansville, IN

Bachelor of Science, Computer Science

Psychology Minor

December 2013

May 2011

### Technical Skills

# Legacy

- COBOL
- CICS
- JCL
- DB2
- RDz/IDz
- Changeman
- IBM Problem

**Determination Tools** 

#### Modern

- Python
- SQL
- Java
- C#
- Angular
- Bootstrap 4
- HTML
- CSS
- Javascript
- IntelliJ
- VBA

#### Other

- JIRA
- Word
- Excel
- PowerPoint
- Visio